[{"question": "What is a view?", "options": ["a)\tAn brief description of the schema diagram.", "b)\tA relation that is not a part of the schema but is a virtual relation", "c)\tAny relation that is a part of the schema", "d)\tA relation that is a part of the schema but which needs to be specified in every operation made on that particular relation."], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "What is the command used to define view in SQL?", "options": ["a)\tdefine view", "b)\tnew view", "c)\tcreate view", "d)\tnone of the mentioned"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "create view studentdet", "options": ["select ID, address, name"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "t is the result of the above query?", "options": ["a)\tIt creates a view named studentdet with 3 attributes", "b)\tIt creates a view named studentdet with 1 attribute", "c)\tIt creates a view named ID with 2 attributes", "d)\tIt is syntactically wrong and does not give a result"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "State true or false: One view can be used in the expression defining another view", "options": ["a)\tTrue", "b)\tFalse"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "If the actual relations used in the view definition change, the view is updated immediately. Such views are called _________", "options": ["a)\tInstant views", "b)\tInstantaneous views", "c)\tMaterialistic views", "d)\tMaterialized views"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "The process of maintaining views up to date is called _________", "options": ["a)\tView maintenance", "b)\tView updating", "c)\tView materialization", "d)\tView isolation"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "How can we insert data into a view?", "options": ["a)\tinsert into <view name=\"\"> (<data>);", "b)\tcreate data <view name=\"\"> values (<data>);", "c)\tenter <view name=\"\"> (<data>);", "d)\tinsert into <view name=\"\"> values (<data>);"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "State true or false: We can update a view if it has multiple database relations in the from clause", "options": ["a)\tTrue", "b)\tFalse"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "A collection of data designed to be used by different people is called a/an", "options": ["a) Organization", "b) Database", "c) Relationship", "d) Schema"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "Which of the following is the oldest database model?", "options": ["a) Relational", "b) Deductive", "c) Physical", "d) Network"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "Which of the following schemas does define a view or views of the database for particular users?", "options": ["a) Internal schema", "b) Conceptual schema", "c) Physical schema", "d) External schema"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "Which of the following is an attribute that can uniquely identify a row in a table?", "options": ["a) Secondary key", "b) Candidate key", "c) Foreign key", "d) Alternate key"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "Which of the following are the process of selecting the data storage and data access characteristics of the database?", "options": ["a) Logical database design", "b) Physical database design", "c) Testing and performance tuning", "d) Evaluation and selecting"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "Which of the following terms does refer to the correctness and completeness of the data in a database?", "options": ["a) Data security", "b) Data constraint", "c) Data independence", "d) Data integrity"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "The relationship between DEPARTMENT and EMPLOYEE is a", "options": ["a) One-to-one relationship", "b) One-to-many relationship", "c) Many-to-many relationship", "d) Many-to-one relationship"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "A table can be logically connected to another table by defining a", "options": ["a) Super key", "b) Candidate key", "c) Primary key", "d) Unique key"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "If the state of the database no longer reflects a real state of the world that the database is supposed to capture, then such a state is called", "options": ["a) Consistent state", "b) Parallel state", "c) Durable state", "d) Inconsistent state"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "Which of the following is a physical storage media?", "options": ["a) Tape Storage", "b) Optical Storage", "c) Flash memory", "d) All of the mentioned"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "The _________ is the fastest and most costly form of storage, which is relatively small; its use is managed by the computer system hardware.", "options": ["a) Cache", "b) Disk", "c) Main memory", "d) Flash memory"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "Which of the following stores several gigabytes of data but usually lost when power failure?", "options": ["a) Flash memory", "b) Disk", "c) Main memory", "d) Secondary memory"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "The flash memory storage used are", "options": ["a) NOR Flash", "b) OR Flash", "c) AND Flash", "d) All of the mentioned"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "__________ is increasingly being used in server systems to improve performance by caching frequently used data, since it provides faster access than disk, with larger storage capacity than main memory.", "options": ["a) Flash memory", "b) Disk", "c) Main memory", "d) Secondary memory"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "Which is the cheapest memory device in terms of costs/ bit?", "options": ["a) Semiconductor memory", "b) Magnetic disks", "c) Compact disks", "d) Magnetic tapes"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "The primary medium for the long-term online storage of data is the __________ where the entire database is stored on magnetic disk.", "options": ["a) Semiconductor memory", "b) Magnetic disks", "c) Compact disks", "d) Magnetic tapes"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "Optical disk _______ systems contain a few drives and numerous disks that can be loaded into one of the drives automatically (by a robot arm) on demand.", "options": ["a) Tape Storage", "b) Jukebox", "c) Flash memory", "d) All of the mentioned"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "There are \u201crecord-once\u201d versions of the compact disk and digital video disk, which can be written only once; such disks are also called __________ disks.", "options": ["a) Write-once, read-many (WORM)", "b) CD-R", "c) DVD-W", "d) CD-ROM"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "A _________ consists of a sequence of query and/or update statements.", "options": ["a) Transaction", "b) Commit", "c) Rollback", "d) Flashback"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "Which of the following makes the transaction permanent in the database?", "options": ["a) View", "b) Commit", "c) Rollback", "d) Flashback"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "In order to undo the work of transaction after last commit which one should be used?", "options": ["a) View", "b) Commit", "c) Rollback", "d) Flashback"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "t does Rollback do?", "options": ["a) Undoes the transactions before commit", "b) Clears all transactions", "c) Redoes the transactions before commit", "d) No action"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "In case of any shut down during transaction before commit which of the following statement is done automatically?", "options": ["a) View", "b) Commit", "c) Rollback", "d) Flashback"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "In order to maintain the consistency during transactions, database provides", "options": ["a) Commit", "b) Atomic", "c) Flashback", "d) Retain"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "Transaction processing is associated with everything below except", "options": ["a) Conforming an action or triggering a response", "b) Producing detail summary or exception report", "c) Recording a business activity", "d) Maintaining a data"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "A transaction completes its execution is said to be", "options": ["a) Committed", "b) Aborted", "c) Rolled back", "d) Failed"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "A __________ is a special kind of a store procedure that executes in response to certain action on the table like insertion, deletion or updation of data.", "options": ["a) Procedures", "b) Triggers", "c) Functions", "d) None of the mentioned"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "Triggers are supported in", "options": ["a) Delete", "b) Update", "c) Views", "d) All of the mentioned"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "The CREATE TRIGGER statement is used to create the trigger. THE _____ clause specifies the table name on which the trigger is to be attached. The ______ specifies that this is an AFTER INSERT trigger.", "options": ["a) for insert, on", "b) On, for insert", "c) For, insert", "d) None of the mentioned"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "What are the after triggers?", "options": ["a) Triggers generated after a particular operation", "b) These triggers run after an insert, update or delete on a table", "c) These triggers run after an insert, views, update or delete on a table", "d) All of the mentioned"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "The variables in the triggers are declared using", "options": ["a) \u2013", "b) @", "c) /", "d) /@"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "The default extension for an Oracle SQL*Plus file is:", "options": ["a) .txt", "b) .pls", "c) .ora", "d) .sql"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "Which of the following is NOT an Oracle-supported trigger?", "options": ["a) BEFORE", "b) DURING", "c) AFTER", "d) INSTEAD OF"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "What are the different in triggers?", "options": ["a) Define, Create", "b) Drop, Comment", "c) Insert, Update, Delete", "d) All of the mentioned"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "Triggers ________ enabled or disabled", "options": ["a) Can be", "b) Cannot be", "c) Ought to be", "d) Always"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "Dynamic hashing allows us to?", "options": ["a)\tAccommodate the growth of the database", "b)\tAccommodate the shrinkage of the database", "c)\tAllows modification of hash function", "d)\tAll of the mentioned"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "Dynamic hashing is also called as _________", "options": ["a)\tExtended hashing", "b)\tExtendable hashing", "c)\tStatic hashing", "d)\tMovable hashing"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "Which of the following operations can be performed on an extendable hash structure?", "options": ["a)\tLookup", "b)\tInsertion", "c)\tDeletion", "d)\tAll of the mentioned"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "The space overhead in dynamic hashing is ________ than that of static hashing", "options": ["a)\tMore", "b)\tLess", "c)\tEqual", "d)\tNone of the mentioned"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage of the dynamic hashing structure", "options": ["a)\tBuckets can be allocated dynamically", "b)\tLookup involves additional level of indirection", "c)\tIt involves a lesser space overhead", "d)\tHash structure can be modified dynamically"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "The form of dynamic hashing that avoids the additional level of indirection is called as  _________", "options": ["a)\tLinear hashing", "b)\tStatic hashing", "c)\tDirective hashing", "d)\tIndirective hashing"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "Hash structures are not the best choice for which of the following?", "options": ["a)\tA search key on which individual point queries are likely", "b)\tA search key which is invalid", "c)\tA search key on which range queries are likely", "d)\tA search key on which multi-level queries are likely"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "Which of the following is an issue that needs to be considered while choosing an indexing technique?", "options": ["a)\tFrequency of insertion and deletion", "b)\tData types of the data", "c)\tNumber of items in the relation", "d)\tNone of the mentioned"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "Which of the following hash function classifies data into least number of buckets?", "options": ["a)\tSum of digits modulo 8", "b)\tSum of digits modulo 5", "c)\tSum of digits modulo 2", "d)\tSum of digits"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "The term ______ is used to denote a unit of storage that can store one or more records", "options": ["a)\tBasket", "b)\tBucket", "c)\tUnit", "d)\tSet"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "If K denotes the set of all the search key values, and B denotes the set of all bucket addresses, a function from K to B is called as __________", "options": ["a)\tBucket function", "b)\tAddress function", "c)\tHash function", "d)\tSearch function"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "In a __________ , we obtain the address of the disk block containing a desired record directly by computing a function on the search key value of the record", "options": ["a)\tHash file organization", "b)\tHash index organization", "c)\tHashing address", "d)\tNone of the mentioned"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "In a __________ we organize the search keys, with their associated pointers, into a hash file structure", "options": ["a)\tHash file organization", "b)\tHash index organization", "c)\tHashing address", "d)\tNone of the mentioned"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "What is a bucket overflow?", "options": ["a)\tWhen a bucket does not have enough space", "b)\tThere are insufficient buckets", "c)\tWhen Bucket skew occurs", "d)\tAll of the mentioned"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "Some buckets are assigned more records than the others which causes bucket overflow, this condition is called as ________", "options": ["a)\tBucket sufficiency", "b)\tBucket insufficiency", "c)\tBucket skew", "d)\tBucket normalcy"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "Overflow handling using a linked list of buckets is called as ____________", "options": ["a)\tBucket chaining", "b)\tOverflow chaining", "c)\tBucket linking", "d)\tOverflow linking"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "State true or false: A hash index organizes the search keys, with their associated pointers, into a hash file structure", "options": ["a)\tTrue", "b)\tFalse"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "Which of the following is the worst hash function among the given choices", "options": ["a)\tThe sum of the digits modulo 8", "b)\tThe sum of the digits modulo 2", "c)\tThe sum of the digits modulo 5", "d)\tThe sum of the digits"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "In ordered indices the file containing the records is sequentially ordered, a ___________ is an index whose search key also defines the sequential order of the file.", "options": ["a) Clustered index", "b) Structured index", "c) Unstructured index", "d) Nonclustered index"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "Indices whose search key specifies an order different from the sequential order of the file are called ___________ indices.", "options": ["a) Nonclustered", "b) Secondary", "c) All of the mentioned", "d) None of the mentioned"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "An ____________ consists of a search-key value and pointers to one or more records with that value as their search-key value.", "options": ["a) Index entry", "b) Index hash", "c) Index cluster", "d) Index map"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "In a _______ clustering index, the index record contains the search-key value and a pointer to the first data record with that search-key value and the rest of the records will be in the sequential pointers.", "options": ["a) Dense", "b) Sparse", "c) Straight", "d) Continuous"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "In a __________ index, an index entry appears for only some of the search-key values.", "options": ["a) Dense", "b) Sparse", "c) Straight", "d) Continuous"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "Incase the indices values are larger, index is created for these values of the index. This is called", "options": ["a) Pointed index", "b) Sequential index", "c) Multilevel index", "d) Multiple index"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "A search key containing more than one attribute is referred to as a _________ search key.", "options": ["a) Simple", "b) Composite", "c) Compound", "d) Secondary"], "answer": "d"}, {"question": "In B+ tree the node which points to another node is called", "options": ["a) Leaf node", "b) External node", "c) Final node", "d) Internal node"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "Insertion of a large number of entries at a time into an index is referred to as __________ of the index.", "options": ["a) Loading", "b) Bulk insertion", "c) Bulk loading", "d) Increase insertion"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "What is the purpose of the index in sql server?", "options": ["a) To enhance the query performance", "b) To provide an index to a record", "c) To perform fast searches", "d) All of the mentioned"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "How many types of indexes are there in sql server?", "options": ["a) 1", "b) 2", "c) 3", "d) 4"], "answer": "c"}, {"question": "How non clustered index point to the data?", "options": ["a) It never points to anything", "b) It points to a data row", "c) It is used for pointing data rows containing key values", "d) None of the mentioned"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "Which one is true about clustered index?", "options": ["a) Clustered index is not associated with table", "b) Clustered index is built by default on unique key columns", "c) Clustered index is not built on unique key columns", "d) None of the mentioned"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "What is true about indexes?", "options": ["a) Indexes enhance the performance even if the table is updated frequently", "b) It makes harder for sql server engines to work to work on index which have large keys", "c) It doesn\u2019t make harder for sql server engines to work to work on index which have large keys", "d) None of the mentioned"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "Does index take space in the disk?", "options": ["a) It stores memory as and when required", "b) Yes, Indexes are stored on disk", "c) Indexes are never stored on disk", "d) Indexes take no space"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "What are composite indexes?", "options": ["a) Are those which are composed by database for its internal use", "b) A composite index is a combination of index on 2 or more columns", "c) Composite index can never be created", "d) None of the mentioned"], "answer": "a"}, {"question": "If an index is _________________ the metadata and statistics continue to exists", "options": ["a) Disabling", "b) Dropping", "c) Altering", "d) Both Disabling and Dropping"], "answer": "b"}, {"question": "In _______________ index instead of storing all the columns for a record together, each column is stored separately with all other rows in an index.", "options": ["a) Clustered", "b) Column store", "c) Non clustered", "d) Row store"], "answer": "c"}]